Bruno P. Kinoshita

1 Courthouse Lane - Auckland 1010 - New Zealand

Brazilian-New Zealander, married, 37 years old, non-smoker

In the past seventeen years I have worked in different industries including telecommunications, banking, credit, retail, insurance, research, government, and start-ups. I had different positions such as programmer, quality engineer, devops, architect, full stack developer, big data engineer, research software engineer, and frontend developer. ORCID ID: https://orcid.org/0000-0001-8250-4074

I am fluent in English and Portuguese. I have an intermediate level of Spanish and Japanese, and basic of French. Attended Te Reo Māori beginner classes to learn basic vocabulary and pronunciation.

Skills

Languages	Java, Python, PHP, R, C/C++, CSS, HTML, JavaScript, Shell, Perl, SQL
Frameworks	Node.js, NumPy, Pandas, Spark, SpringBoot, FastAPI, Flask, Tornado, Laravel
Systems	Linux, OSX, Windows
Other	Open Source, GIS, Semantic Web, Linked Data, Natural Language Processing,
	Bioinformatics (BioUno.org)

Achievements

o GSoC Mentor, Jenkins Machine Learning Plug-in	March 2020, to September 2020
o Invited to become an Apache Software Foundation Member	March 2018
o Spirit of GovHack for amazing team work	July 2016
o NIWA Proactive Communicator	February 2016
o Organized two Jenkins meetups in Sao Paulo, Brazil	2012 and 2013

Education

o Diploma in Business Administration, Mackenzie University	January 2008 – July 2009
o BSc Information Systems, Mackenzie University	August 2003 – July 2007

Training

o <i>Vue 3 + Typescript</i> . Vue Mastery. Online.	2021
o Pandas. Kaggle. Online (Kaggle).	2020
o Intro to Machine Learning. Kaggle. Online (Kaggle).	2020
o Building Web Applications in R with Shiny. DataCamp. Online.	2018
o OWASP NZ Day Advanced Web Hacking and Secure Coding. University of Auckland. Auckla Zealand.	nd, New 2017
o AWS Concepts. Linux Academy. Online.	2016
o Apache Spark Essentials. Linux Academy. Online.	2016
o Metabarcoding (Winter Bootcamp). University of Auckland. Auckland, New Zealand.	2016
o Transcriptomics (Winter Bootcamp). University of Auckland. Auckland, New Zealand.	2016
o <i>Microbiology and Forensic Science (MicFor)</i> . Jordan University of Science and Technologya. O Open2Study.	nline via 2016
o Statistics and R for the Life Sciences. edX. Online.	2015
o NCBI Now! An online workshop that introduces NGS with a hands-on component in the cloud Online ORAU Portal.	d!. NCBI. 2015

o Web Development with Servlets and JSP. Sun Microsystems. Sao Paulo, Brazil.	
o COBIT and Sarbanes-Oxley. Claro. Sao Paulo, Brazil.	2006
o Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate career. Bras e Figueiredo. Sao Paulo, Br	azil. 2003
Experience	
o Research Software Engineer, NIWA	Oct 2018 – Oct 2021
- Working with NIWA/NZ, BOM/AU, and MO/UK remotely from Auckland o	n Cylc workflow manager
using JupyterHub, Python Tornado and JavaScript Vue.js.	
o Java Engineer, N/WA	Jun 2017 – Sep 2018
- Java JEE development for EcoConnect web services, serving NIWA climate d	
Fire Services NZ, Maori TV, DOC-NZ, energy and insurance companies, etc.	
o Full Stack Software Developer, Spark Ventures	Oct 2016 – Jun 2017
- AWS development, build systems, and Java development using SpringBoot.	
o Software Developer / Operations, NIWA	Apr 2015 – Sep 2016
- Configuration management with Puppet and Ansible, automation, Jav	a development, CI and
DevOps pipelines mainly with Jenkins.	L 0014 M 0015
o Senior Big Data Engineer, Boa Vista Servicos (Equifax)	Jun 2014 – Mar 2015
- Impala, HDFS, Hadoop . Cobol and Java development. Creation of Big Data	business cases for execute
and management teams.	L. 2012 M. 2014
o Senior Software Architect, <i>Tokio Marine</i>	Jan 2013 – May 2014
- ActiveMQ cluster, internal workshops and trainings, internal web services,	330 , integration of new
Portal with Liferay. Company-wide KPI monitoring implementation.	O-1-0010 D 0010
o Senior Infrastructure Engineer, Tokio Marine	Oct 2012 – Dec 2013
- Automation with Jenkins and Puppet.	O-+ 2011 C 2012
o Senior Software Engineer, Tokio Marine	Oct 2011 – Sep 2012
- Java web development with Servlets, Portlets, and LifeRay modules. SSO wit	in OpenAivi , QA environ-
ment with Jenkins , Ivy, and other tools.	I.J 2011 Can 2011
o Senior System Analyst, Lojas Riachuelo	Jul 2011 – Sep 2011
- Java Swing development for retail POS system.	lan 2010 lun 2011
 Senior Software Quality Engineer, Vivo (Telefonica) CRM development with Java and GWT. QA pipeline set up with Hudso 	Jan 2010 – Jun 2011 on (now Jenkins), Sonar,
Testlink, FishEye, and JIRA.	
o Senior Software Engineer, Nossa Caixa Bank	Apr 2008 – Dec 2009
NET C# and Java support development. Integration with Mainframes	using Cobol, MQSeries
DirectConnect, Uniface, and Java in Z/OS Linux.	I 2007 May 2000
o Junior System Analyst, Claro	Jun 2007 – Mar 2008
- Java web development and J2EE using Servlets, EJBs, JMS.	Inn 2006 May 2007
o Junior System Technician, Claro	Jan 2006 – May 2007
 Java Swing and J2EE. Value Added Services intern, Claro 	Jul 2004 – Dec 2005
- VAS middleware systems, billing integration, Java development on HP-UX ar	
Certifications	
o gvSIG User Certificate	2018
-	
o LFCE Linux Foundation Certified Engineer	2015
o Professional Scrum Master I (scrum.org)	2011
o ISTQB CTFL Certified Tester	2010
o SCWCD Sun Certified Web Component Developer	2009
o ITIL Foundation V2	2009
o COBIT Foundation V4.1	2009

2006

2003

o SCJP Sun Certified Java Programmer

o MCP Microsoft Certified Professional Windows 2000